发生什么事了
What happened?
那只海洋生物把它撞烂了
That sea creature rammed it.
它可不是只普通的海洋生物  孩子们
Not just any sea creature, boys.
它是一只玛尔波莎
That's a marposa.
什么  这不可能啊
What? That doesn't make any sense.
我和家人在旅途中遇见过一群玛尔波莎
My family and I saw a whole pod on the voyage here,
但它们很友善啊
but they were friendly.
它们哪里看着友善了
Does that look friendly to you?
不是  但
No, but--
指挥中心
To the command center.
-我们必须制定一套攻击方案  -攻击
- We must devise a plan of attack. - Attack?
赫克特国王  我知道我只是一名新来的统治者
King Hector, I know I'm a new ruler,
但或许还有其它解决办法
but maybe there's another way.
只有一种办法能对付那种生物  艾莲娜
There's only one way to deal with a creature like that, Elena.
我的办法
My way.
也许我们应该再考虑一下  赫克特
Perhaps we should think this through, Hector.
让我来捋捋
So let me get it straight.
你这么说摆明就是不想要
What you're saying is you don't want
我那条无敌海上战船了
my new Sea Blaster ship.
我们开始策划攻击方案吧
Let's start planning that attack.
-多谢你的支持  -但我不知道
- Glad you agree. - But I don't know--
艾莲娜  你说过你的家人在附近
Elena, you said you had family nearby.
我是说过
I do.
那好  为什么你不去联系他们
Okay, why don't you check on them
确保他们此刻的安全呢
and make sure they're safe.
对  当然
Right. Of course.
很好  这下总算能安心开始策划我们的攻击了
Good. Now we can plan our attack in peace.
跟我来  小的们
Come on, boys.
噢  在那儿
Ooh, over there.
看到那些裂痕了吗  我想它很快就要孵化了
See those cracks? I think it might hatch soon.
伊莎贝尔
Isabel!
艾莲娜
Elena!
大家都还好吗
Is everyone all right here?
我们没事啊  怎么了
We're fine. Why?
一只玛尔波莎攻击了拉贾国王的船
A marposa attacked King Raja's ship.
不可能啊
That doesn't make any sense.
我的书上说它们是不伤人的
My book says they're harmless,
而且生活在远海  除非
and stay way out at sea, except...
除非什么
Except when?
除非玛尔波莎妈妈到岸上下蛋
When the female marposa comes to shore to lay her eggs.
书上说玛尔波莎宝宝离开母亲
It says here that baby marposas get very upset
就会感到非常不安
if they're separated from their mothers.
它们会因为害怕而四处拍打
They thrash around because they're scared.
甚至会变得很危险
They can even be dangerous,
但一旦它们找到了妈妈就会立刻安静下来
but they calm right down once they find their mom.
所以也许那只破坏客船的玛尔波莎
So maybe the marposa that destroyed the ship
是一只离开了妈妈的宝宝
was a baby separated from its mother.
一定发生在它孵化之后
It must've happened after it hatched.
因为当宝宝们跟着妈妈时
Because when the baby is with its mom,
它很快乐  就像那只一样
it's happy, like that one.
所以我们一定要找到那只玛尔泊莎的妈妈
So we have to find the marposa's mother.
但怎么找呢
But how?
它们通过口哨来交流
Hm. They communicate by whistling.
如果玛尔波莎妈妈在寻找它的孩子
If the mom is looking for her baby,
她就会发出哨声
she'd be whistling.
也许你的磁力喇叭可以帮我们定位到它
Maybe your magnaphone can help us locate her.
好主意  嘿  接着
Great idea. Here, take it.
但首先我得告知其它国王它只是个宝宝
But first I have to tell the other kings it's just a baby.
阿芒多  你看到那只玛尔波莎了吗
Armando, did you see the marposa?
它肯定看到了我
And it sure saw me.
我们会把那怪物诱出海面并抓住它  是的
We are gonna lure the creature out to sea and capture it, yes!
现在卸下绳索吧
Now let's cast off.
赫克特国王  等等
King Hector, wait!
你这么快就回来了
Oh, back so soon?
您必须停止进攻
You have to stop the attack.
我想那只玛尔波莎只是一只吓坏的宝宝
I think the marposa is just a scared baby.
只要我们帮它找到妈妈
If we help it find its mother,
它就会离开您的船
it'll leave your ships alone.
各就各位  把渔网安装好
Men, let's get that net set up.
您必须听我说  赫克特国王
You have to listen to me, King Hector.
不  你得听我的
No. You have to listen to me.
但您的所作所为是错的
But what you're doing is wrong.
拉兹潘  你认为我做错了吗
Larzipan, do you think I'm wrong?
-当然没有  -拉吉内托
- Of course not. - Rajinator?
您从未在任何事上犯过错
You've never been wrong about anything.
伯尼尼
Bonini?
我知道这件事我是对的  华金
I know I'm right about this, Joaquin.
你必须相信我
You have to believe me.
你想得到那条船  对吧  那你加不加入
You want that ship, don't you? Are you in or out?
我加入
I'm in.
艾莲娜  你加不加入
Elena, are you in or out?
我不做
I'm out.
我们走  斯凯勒
Let's go, Skylar.
-听到什么了吗  -还没
- Hear anything? - Not yet.
也许我们应该换一条路
Maybe we should go back the other way.
等等
Wait.
听到了吗
Do you hear that?
听着像是玛尔波莎的声音
Sounds like a marposa to me.
和那只宝宝的哨声一样
It's the same whistle as the baby.
一定是它妈妈
It must be the mother.
从那个小岛上传来的
It's coming from that little island.
我们去看看
Let's check it out.
在那里  它被卡在树根里了
There. She's trapped in those roots.
这就能解释为什么宝宝是单只的了
That would explain why the baby's alone.
根本挪不动
It won't budge.
你可以把它拉松开吗  斯凯勒
Do you think you can pull it loose, Skylar?
交给我吧  公主
You got it, princesa.
我是一只大力的飞虎
I am a mighty jaquin.
你折断不了我
You will not break me.
但我会折断你
I will break you!
嗷  要断了  要断了  要断了
Ow! Splinter, splinter, splinter!